<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Ben Leskey's Blog: cdda_erik</title>
		<description>cdda_erik posts from Ben Leskey</description>
		<link>https://benleskey.com/blog/tags/cdda_erik</link>
		<language>en-us</language>
		<copyright>2023 Ben Leskey</copyright>
		<lastBuildDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 15:50:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Mar 2023 15:50:18 +0000</pubDate>
		<atom:link href="https://benleskey.com/blog/tags/cdda_erik.feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

		<item>
	<title>Erik Otto #5: Gaining allies</title>
	<description>Exploration Before any high-level raiding, Erik wants more allies and resources. There is no more postal service or Amazon, so he goes exploring with Alejandro Quick. Up around the big city should be rich pickings. There’s an armored car along the side of the road with two turrets mounted on top. Erik and Alejandro pull over beside it and strip out the turrets for later. These turret mounts are the first step in a fully-automated laser defense system mounted on top of a vehicle. Such defenses would make raiding cities almost a breeze. Erik and Alejandro tear through a horde…</description>
	<category>games</category><category>letsplay</category><category>cdda</category><category>cdda_erik</category>
	<link>https://benleskey.com/blog/cdda_erik_5</link>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://benleskey.com/blog/cdda_erik_5</guid>
	<pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Erik Otto #4: Arsenal</title>
	<description>With lockpicks in hand, Erik drives out to the wind turbines to pick their locks and survey the area. It takes him nearly the whole day to pick one of the locks, stopping to eat cake and drink water for lunch. Finally! He picks the lock, and at the same time gains proficiency in picking locks, which will make the other wind turbines much faster. After climbing to the top, he gains a wide view of the surrounding area. Before heading to the next wind turbine, Erik decides to complete the mission given by Smokes the refugee center merchant and…</description>
	<category>games</category><category>letsplay</category><category>cdda</category><category>cdda_erik</category>
	<link>https://benleskey.com/blog/cdda_erik_4</link>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://benleskey.com/blog/cdda_erik_4</guid>
	<pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Erik Otto #3: Preparing for battle</title>
	<description>Now that the base is set up, Erik can start more organized exploration and raids. To manage having a large number of followers—when he gets them—he needs to set up stations for people to suit up and suit down. Organizing gear First, Erik crafts a washing kit and washes up some holsters and sheaths he took off zombie corpses while raiding light industry compounds. Full outfits go into the clothes room. Currently there isn’t much difference, but in the future there may be full hazmat outfits, melee raiding outfits, summer outfits, etc. Weapons—including slings, holsters, sheaths, and the like—go into…</description>
	<category>games</category><category>letsplay</category><category>cdda</category><category>cdda_erik</category>
	<link>https://benleskey.com/blog/cdda_erik_3</link>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://benleskey.com/blog/cdda_erik_3</guid>
	<pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Erik Otto #2: Base building and car collecting</title>
	<description>Erik and Alejandro have established a base, but now they need supplies, food, weapons, and vehicles. It’s time to go exploring and looting. They purchase ammunition from the refugee center by trading novels—apparently the refugees love reading—and hit the road in their RV. Tools are the first priority, so they can get vehicles working and build up their base. The light industry scattered around the map are too valuable a target, with all the tools that can be found there. Erik and Alejandro move in guns blazing, Erik with his Uzi and Alejandro with his Glock 19. The battle is…</description>
	<category>games</category><category>letsplay</category><category>cdda</category><category>cdda_erik</category>
	<link>https://benleskey.com/blog/cdda_erik_2</link>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://benleskey.com/blog/cdda_erik_2</guid>
	<pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Erik Otto #1: Used car cult salesman</title>
	<description>Intro It’s time for a new Cataclysm: Dark Days Ahead let’s play! Erik Otto is a former used car salesman shunted away to one of the many FEMA evacuation shelters during the end of the world. He’s extremely intelligent, very sociable, and attractive. If he hadn’t been a used car salesman, he always thought that he’d make a good cult leader. Well, now that the apocalypse has arrived, now is the chance for the Cult of Erik to arise. This character is designed to attract NPCs and become a sort of hub for an NPC enclave. Using a “debug” menu…</description>
	<category>games</category><category>letsplay</category><category>cdda</category><category>cdda_erik</category>
	<link>https://benleskey.com/blog/cdda_erik_1</link>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://benleskey.com/blog/cdda_erik_1</guid>
	<pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>_
	</channel>
</rss>
