<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Ben Leskey's Blog: discovery</title>
		<description>discovery posts from Ben Leskey</description>
		<link>https://benleskey.com/blog/tags/discovery</link>
		<language>en-us</language>
		<copyright>2023 Ben Leskey</copyright>
		<lastBuildDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 06:48:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
		<pubDate>Wed, 15 Feb 2023 06:48:10 +0000</pubDate>
		<atom:link href="https://benleskey.com/blog/tags/discovery.feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

		<item>
	<title>Discovering random websites</title>
	<description>The other day I was found by diff.blog who starred the repository for this website on Github. While poking around their bot’s Github account I found that the diffblogbot stars page is a huge mine for random personal websites scattered around Github. diffblogbot crawls for blogs and gathers them all here, in one place. I decided to take a look at some of them, and gather a few of the most interesting in a kind of showcase. Mocha2007’s personal website has a ton of interesting stuff: conlangs, games, toy programs, and more! Their conlangs and worldbuilding are very detailed, just…</description>
	<category>discovery</category>
	<link>https://benleskey.com/blog/discovering_random_websites</link>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://benleskey.com/blog/discovering_random_websites</guid>
	<pubDate>Thu, 26 Jan 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Finding discussion about diff.blog</title>
	<description>I couldn’t find much about diff.blog with a cursory glance over the internet, so I went looking. On diff.blog itself I discovered a post from Roman Martin’s blog when diff.blog found him back in 2020 the same way they did me recently. Here’s a Hacker News subthread from 2020, where the creator of diff.blog, Vishnu KS, is promoting it. Here’s a smaller subthread from 2022, and another subthread from 2021, and one more from 2020. One of the HN threads was linked in a blog post from jerieljan. There’ve been HN submissions of diff.blog, and a Reddit post, but none…</description>
	<category>discovery</category><category>deepdive</category>
	<link>https://benleskey.com/blog/finding_discussion_diff_blog</link>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://benleskey.com/blog/finding_discussion_diff_blog</guid>
	<pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
_
	</channel>
</rss>
