<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Ben Leskey's Blog: games</title>
		<description>games posts from Ben Leskey</description>
		<link>https://benleskey.com/blog/tags/games</link>
		<language>en-us</language>
		<copyright>2023 Ben Leskey</copyright>
		<lastBuildDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2023 02:12:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
		<pubDate>Wed, 29 Mar 2023 02:12:12 +0000</pubDate>
		<atom:link href="https://benleskey.com/blog/tags/games.feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

		<item>
	<title>30th DCSS win: Octopode Cinder Acolyte of Jiyva</title>
	<description>I successfully ascended with my 30th win in the Dungeon Crawl: Stone Soup roguelike, playing an Octopode Cinder Acolyte of Jiyva. This was a really fun run, relying on Statue Form and Dragon’s Call by the end. Dragon’s Call, in particular, seems like one of the most powerful, if not the most powerful, spells. The morgue file from CKO is included below:…</description>
	<category>games</category><category>dcss</category>
	<link>https://benleskey.com/blog/opca_win</link>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://benleskey.com/blog/opca_win</guid>
	<pubDate>Tue, 28 Mar 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Erik Otto #5: Gaining allies</title>
	<description>Exploration Before any high-level raiding, Erik wants more allies and resources. There is no more postal service or Amazon, so he goes exploring with Alejandro Quick. Up around the big city should be rich pickings. There’s an armored car along the side of the road with two turrets mounted on top. Erik and Alejandro pull over beside it and strip out the turrets for later. These turret mounts are the first step in a fully-automated laser defense system mounted on top of a vehicle. Such defenses would make raiding cities almost a breeze. Erik and Alejandro tear through a horde…</description>
	<category>games</category><category>letsplay</category><category>cdda</category><category>cdda_erik</category>
	<link>https://benleskey.com/blog/cdda_erik_5</link>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://benleskey.com/blog/cdda_erik_5</guid>
	<pubDate>Tue, 14 Feb 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Erik Otto #4: Arsenal</title>
	<description>With lockpicks in hand, Erik drives out to the wind turbines to pick their locks and survey the area. It takes him nearly the whole day to pick one of the locks, stopping to eat cake and drink water for lunch. Finally! He picks the lock, and at the same time gains proficiency in picking locks, which will make the other wind turbines much faster. After climbing to the top, he gains a wide view of the surrounding area. Before heading to the next wind turbine, Erik decides to complete the mission given by Smokes the refugee center merchant and…</description>
	<category>games</category><category>letsplay</category><category>cdda</category><category>cdda_erik</category>
	<link>https://benleskey.com/blog/cdda_erik_4</link>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://benleskey.com/blog/cdda_erik_4</guid>
	<pubDate>Wed, 08 Feb 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Erik Otto #3: Preparing for battle</title>
	<description>Now that the base is set up, Erik can start more organized exploration and raids. To manage having a large number of followers—when he gets them—he needs to set up stations for people to suit up and suit down. Organizing gear First, Erik crafts a washing kit and washes up some holsters and sheaths he took off zombie corpses while raiding light industry compounds. Full outfits go into the clothes room. Currently there isn’t much difference, but in the future there may be full hazmat outfits, melee raiding outfits, summer outfits, etc. Weapons—including slings, holsters, sheaths, and the like—go into…</description>
	<category>games</category><category>letsplay</category><category>cdda</category><category>cdda_erik</category>
	<link>https://benleskey.com/blog/cdda_erik_3</link>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://benleskey.com/blog/cdda_erik_3</guid>
	<pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Erik Otto #2: Base building and car collecting</title>
	<description>Erik and Alejandro have established a base, but now they need supplies, food, weapons, and vehicles. It’s time to go exploring and looting. They purchase ammunition from the refugee center by trading novels—apparently the refugees love reading—and hit the road in their RV. Tools are the first priority, so they can get vehicles working and build up their base. The light industry scattered around the map are too valuable a target, with all the tools that can be found there. Erik and Alejandro move in guns blazing, Erik with his Uzi and Alejandro with his Glock 19. The battle is…</description>
	<category>games</category><category>letsplay</category><category>cdda</category><category>cdda_erik</category>
	<link>https://benleskey.com/blog/cdda_erik_2</link>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://benleskey.com/blog/cdda_erik_2</guid>
	<pubDate>Mon, 06 Feb 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Erik Otto #1: Used car cult salesman</title>
	<description>Intro It’s time for a new Cataclysm: Dark Days Ahead let’s play! Erik Otto is a former used car salesman shunted away to one of the many FEMA evacuation shelters during the end of the world. He’s extremely intelligent, very sociable, and attractive. If he hadn’t been a used car salesman, he always thought that he’d make a good cult leader. Well, now that the apocalypse has arrived, now is the chance for the Cult of Erik to arise. This character is designed to attract NPCs and become a sort of hub for an NPC enclave. Using a “debug” menu…</description>
	<category>games</category><category>letsplay</category><category>cdda</category><category>cdda_erik</category>
	<link>https://benleskey.com/blog/cdda_erik_1</link>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://benleskey.com/blog/cdda_erik_1</guid>
	<pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>CDDA let's play: Post-mortem</title>
	<description>I tried my hand at a Cataclysm: Dark Days Ahead screenshot and text let’s play, featuring Raymon Ortega: Would-be Wizard. It was really fun to write, but there’s a few points I’ll remember for next time: Choose a more active start. Most of this let’s play wasn’t very exciting, just trying to get to the refugee center. There wasn’t much action. Maybe a megacity playthrough? Build more story. Getting missions and/or goals sooner will give drive to the character and make the story interesting. Play patiently. The LP can be built slowly; no need to rush objectives. Raymon probably didn’t…</description>
	<category>games</category><category>letsplay</category><category>cdda</category><category>cdda_raymon</category>
	<link>https://benleskey.com/blog/cdda_raymon_postmortem</link>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://benleskey.com/blog/cdda_raymon_postmortem</guid>
	<pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Raymon Ortega #4: The End</title>
	<description>In the previous episode: Raymon camped out for a couple nights below a city, looting and fighting. After looting and fighting for a while, and discovering there was no way around the city from where he was, he hopped into his SUV and backtracked to try and find an off-road path back to a route toward the refugee center. First leg Sure enough, Raymon finds road just ahead, and it’s leading east-west! This could be his ticket to the refugee center. There’s a light industrial compound built right next to the road, and it doesn’t look very infested with the…</description>
	<category>games</category><category>letsplay</category><category>cdda</category><category>cdda_raymon</category>
	<link>https://benleskey.com/blog/cdda_raymon_4</link>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://benleskey.com/blog/cdda_raymon_4</guid>
	<pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Raymon Ortega #3: Camping out of town</title>
	<description>First Night Raymon needs more supplies. He’d like a map of the area; extra food is good; tools would be useful. It’s almost nightfall; he’s spent the whole day traveling toward the refugee center, but now he’s stuck just outside a city of unknown dimensions. The zombies can’t see very far at night, so Raymon plans to raid some of the houses for supplies as soon as nightfall comes. It’s time to set up camp. His camp is barebones, just a tent and a car, but it’s better than nothing. The tent ensures no zombies (or aliens, for that matter)…</description>
	<category>games</category><category>letsplay</category><category>cdda</category><category>cdda_raymon</category>
	<link>https://benleskey.com/blog/cdda_raymon_3</link>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://benleskey.com/blog/cdda_raymon_3</guid>
	<pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Raymon Ortega #2: Battery Heist and a Sweet Chariot</title>
	<description>On foot Last we left Raymon, he had scrounged together some meagre gear and a sturdy spear and was about to hike north west toward the refugee center. Striking out across the field, Raymon headed toward the regional dump near the evac shelter. It wasn’t far as the crow flies, though not connected by road anywhere nearby. This is some form of otherworldly hound. Lean and hungry-looking, its twisted red flesh is stretched tightly across its misshapen, angular frame. Loping grotesquely along, its unusually long neck stretches forward, its skull-like head near the ground as it sniffs out its prey.…</description>
	<category>games</category><category>letsplay</category><category>cdda</category><category>cdda_raymon</category>
	<link>https://benleskey.com/blog/cdda_raymon_2</link>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://benleskey.com/blog/cdda_raymon_2</guid>
	<pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Raymon Ortega #2: Battery Heist and a Sweet Chariot</title>
	<description>On foot Last we left Raymon, he had scrounged together some meagre gear and a sturdy spear and was about to hike north west toward the refugee center. Striking out across the field, Raymon headed toward the regional dump near the evac shelter. It wasn’t far as the crow flies, though not connected by road anywhere nearby. This is some form of otherworldly hound. Lean and hungry-looking, its twisted red flesh is stretched tightly across its misshapen, angular frame. Loping grotesquely along, its unusually long neck stretches forward, its skull-like head near the ground as it sniffs out its prey.…</description>
	<category>games</category><category>letsplay</category><category>cdda</category><category>cdda_raymon</category>
	<link>https://benleskey.com/blog/cdda_raymon_2</link>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://benleskey.com/blog/cdda_raymon_2</guid>
	<pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Raymon Ortega #2: Battery Heist and a Sweet Chariot</title>
	<description>On foot Last we left Raymon, he had scrounged together some meagre gear and a sturdy spear and was about to hike north west toward the refugee center. Striking out across the field, Raymon headed toward the regional dump near the evac shelter. It wasn’t far as the crow flies, though not connected by road anywhere nearby. This is some form of otherworldly hound. Lean and hungry-looking, its twisted red flesh is stretched tightly across its misshapen, angular frame. Loping grotesquely along, its unusually long neck stretches forward, its skull-like head near the ground as it sniffs out its prey.…</description>
	<category>games</category><category>letsplay</category><category>cdda</category><category>cdda_raymon</category>
	<link>https://benleskey.com/blog/cdda_raymon_2</link>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://benleskey.com/blog/cdda_raymon_2</guid>
	<pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>_
	</channel>
</rss>
