<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Ben Leskey's Blog: games</title>
		<description>games posts from Ben Leskey</description>
		<link>https://benleskey.com/blog/tags/games</link>
		<language>en-us</language>
		<copyright>2023 Ben Leskey</copyright>
		<lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 17:31:56 +0000</lastBuildDate>
		<pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 17:31:56 +0000</pubDate>
		<atom:link href="https://benleskey.com/blog/tags/games.feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

		<item>
	<title>Raymon Ortega #2: Battery Heist</title>
	<description>On foot Campground Battery heist On the road again On foot Last we left Raymon, he had scrounged together some meagre gear and a sturdy spear and was about to hike north west toward the refugee center. Striking out across the field, Raymon headed toward the regional dump near the evac shelter. It wasn’t far as the crow flies, though not connected by road anywhere nearby. This is some form of otherworldly hound. Lean and hungry-looking, its twisted red flesh is stretched tightly across its misshapen, angular frame. Loping grotesquely along, its unusually long neck stretches forward, its skull-like head…</description>
	<category>games</category><category>letsplay</category><category>cdda</category><category>cdda_raymon</category>
	<link>https://benleskey.com/blog/cdda_raymon_2</link>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://benleskey.com/blog/cdda_raymon_2</guid>
	<pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Raymon Ortega #1: Would-be Wizard</title>
	<description>I’m starting a new Cataclysm: Dark Days Ahead (CDDA) game, and I thought’d be cool to document my adventures. Maybe it’ll force me to play more thoughtfully, not falling victim to that classic killer of permadeath roguelikes: Hubris. Cataclysm: Dark Days Ahead is a turn-based survival game set in a post-apocalyptic world. Struggle to survive in a harsh, persistent, procedurally generated world. Scavenge the remnants of a dead civilization for food, equipment, or, if you are lucky, a vehicle with a full tank of gas to get you the hell out of Dodge. Fight to defeat or escape from a…</description>
	<category>games</category><category>letsplay</category><category>cdda</category><category>cdda_raymon</category>
	<link>https://benleskey.com/blog/cdda_raymon_1</link>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://benleskey.com/blog/cdda_raymon_1</guid>
	<pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>29th DCSS win: Naga Hexslinger</title>
	<description>I just got my 29th win in the Dungeon Crawl: Stone Soup roguelike, playing a Naga Hexslinger of Hep. The morgue file from CKO is included below:…</description>
	<category>games</category><category>dcss</category>
	<link>https://benleskey.com/blog/naga_hexslinger_win</link>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://benleskey.com/blog/naga_hexslinger_win</guid>
	<pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
_
	</channel>
</rss>
