<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Ben Leskey's Blog: letsplay</title>
		<description>letsplay posts from Ben Leskey</description>
		<link>https://benleskey.com/blog/tags/letsplay</link>
		<language>en-us</language>
		<copyright>2023 Ben Leskey</copyright>
		<lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2023 22:29:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
		<pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2023 22:29:45 +0000</pubDate>
		<atom:link href="https://benleskey.com/blog/tags/letsplay.feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

		<item>
	<title>Erik Otto #1: Used car cult salesman</title>
	<description>Intro It’s time for a new Cataclysm: Dark Days Ahead let’s play! Erik Otto is a former used car salesman shunted away to one of the many FEMA evacuation shelters during the end of the world. He’s extremely intelligent, very sociable, and attractive. If he hadn’t been a used car salesman, he always thought that he’d make a good cult leader. Well, now that the apocalypse has arrived, now is the chance for the Cult of Erik to arise. This character is designed to attract NPCs and become a sort of hub for an NPC enclave. Using a “debug” menu…</description>
	<category>games</category><category>letsplay</category><category>cdda</category><category>cdda_erik</category>
	<link>https://benleskey.com/blog/cdda_erik_1</link>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://benleskey.com/blog/cdda_erik_1</guid>
	<pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>CDDA let's play: Post-mortem</title>
	<description>I tried my hand at a Cataclysm: Dark Days Ahead screenshot and text let’s play, featuring Raymon Ortega: Would-be Wizard. It was really fun to write, but there’s a few points I’ll remember for next time: Choose a more active start. Most of this let’s play wasn’t very exciting, just trying to get to the refugee center. There wasn’t much action. Maybe a megacity playthrough? Build more story. Getting missions and/or goals sooner will give drive to the character and make the story interesting. Play patiently. The LP can be built slowly; no need to rush objectives. Raymon probably didn’t…</description>
	<category>games</category><category>letsplay</category><category>cdda</category><category>cdda_raymon</category>
	<link>https://benleskey.com/blog/cdda_raymon_postmortem</link>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://benleskey.com/blog/cdda_raymon_postmortem</guid>
	<pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Raymon Ortega #4: The End</title>
	<description>In the previous episode: Raymon camped out for a couple nights below a city, looting and fighting. After looting and fighting for a while, and discovering there was no way around the city from where he was, he hopped into his SUV and backtracked to try and find an off-road path back to a route toward the refugee center. First leg Sure enough, Raymon finds road just ahead, and it’s leading east-west! This could be his ticket to the refugee center. There’s a light industrial compound built right next to the road, and it doesn’t look very infested with the…</description>
	<category>games</category><category>letsplay</category><category>cdda</category><category>cdda_raymon</category>
	<link>https://benleskey.com/blog/cdda_raymon_4</link>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://benleskey.com/blog/cdda_raymon_4</guid>
	<pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Raymon Ortega #3: Camping out of town</title>
	<description>First Night Raymon needs more supplies. He’d like a map of the area; extra food is good; tools would be useful. It’s almost nightfall; he’s spent the whole day traveling toward the refugee center, but now he’s stuck just outside a city of unknown dimensions. The zombies can’t see very far at night, so Raymon plans to raid some of the houses for supplies as soon as nightfall comes. It’s time to set up camp. His camp is barebones, just a tent and a car, but it’s better than nothing. The tent ensures no zombies (or aliens, for that matter)…</description>
	<category>games</category><category>letsplay</category><category>cdda</category><category>cdda_raymon</category>
	<link>https://benleskey.com/blog/cdda_raymon_3</link>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://benleskey.com/blog/cdda_raymon_3</guid>
	<pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Raymon Ortega #2: Battery Heist and a Sweet Chariot</title>
	<description>On foot Last we left Raymon, he had scrounged together some meagre gear and a sturdy spear and was about to hike north west toward the refugee center. Striking out across the field, Raymon headed toward the regional dump near the evac shelter. It wasn’t far as the crow flies, though not connected by road anywhere nearby. This is some form of otherworldly hound. Lean and hungry-looking, its twisted red flesh is stretched tightly across its misshapen, angular frame. Loping grotesquely along, its unusually long neck stretches forward, its skull-like head near the ground as it sniffs out its prey.…</description>
	<category>games</category><category>letsplay</category><category>cdda</category><category>cdda_raymon</category>
	<link>https://benleskey.com/blog/cdda_raymon_2</link>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://benleskey.com/blog/cdda_raymon_2</guid>
	<pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Raymon Ortega #1: Would-be Wizard</title>
	<description>I’m starting a new Cataclysm: Dark Days Ahead (CDDA) game, and I thought’d be cool to document my adventures. Maybe it’ll force me to play more thoughtfully, not falling victim to that classic killer of permadeath roguelikes: Hubris. Cataclysm: Dark Days Ahead is a turn-based survival game set in a post-apocalyptic world. Struggle to survive in a harsh, persistent, procedurally generated world. Scavenge the remnants of a dead civilization for food, equipment, or, if you are lucky, a vehicle with a full tank of gas to get you the hell out of Dodge. Fight to defeat or escape from a…</description>
	<category>games</category><category>letsplay</category><category>cdda</category><category>cdda_raymon</category>
	<link>https://benleskey.com/blog/cdda_raymon_1</link>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://benleskey.com/blog/cdda_raymon_1</guid>
	<pubDate>Sun, 29 Jan 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
_
	</channel>
</rss>
