<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
	<channel>
		<title>Ben Leskey's Blog: software</title>
		<description>software posts from Ben Leskey</description>
		<link>https://benleskey.com/blog/tags/software</link>
		<language>en-us</language>
		<copyright>2023 Ben Leskey</copyright>
		<lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 19:08:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 19:08:49 +0000</pubDate>
		<atom:link href="https://benleskey.com/blog/tags/software.feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />

		<item>
	<title>More RSS feeds!</title>
	<description>I’ve added more RSS feeds, one for each blog tag. This allows people to subscribe to only, say, the mappingtool tag. I can, in this way, use my blog easily as a set of smaller blogs for each category. This took just a bit of work in the website build script; and I cleaned it up a bit so it doesn’t commit temporary files and doesn’t need to work so hard to find the root of the website when I’m already passing that information in the script. I do need to refactor it more, it’s getting rather unwieldy, though still…</description>
	<category>software</category><category>website</category>
	<link>https://benleskey.com/blog/more_rss_feeds</link>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://benleskey.com/blog/more_rss_feeds</guid>
	<pubDate>Fri, 27 Jan 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>I'm on diff.blog</title>
	<description>I saw yesterday that diff.blog’s bot account on Github had starred the repository for this website. I clicked through to their Github page, which described diff.blog as an aggregator of developer blogs… started in 2019 to improve the visibility of self hosted blogs. I followed the directions in their README and signed in to diff.blog with my Github account. Once there, I added the URL of my blog to my account settings and diff.blog crawled my RSS feed. Once I saw how it was using the RSS item descriptions to generate summaries, I improved my build script to actually generate…</description>
	<category>software</category><category>website</category>
	<link>https://benleskey.com/blog/diff_blog</link>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://benleskey.com/blog/diff_blog</guid>
	<pubDate>Wed, 25 Jan 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>I made an RSS feed!</title>
	<description>I made an RSS feed for my blog! It’s a really simple format; I was able to implement my feed just by following the RSS 2.0 spec. Of course, RSS readers are a little less common than they were a decade ago; but there are plenty of extensions for Firefox—I’m using RSSPreview just to test the feed—and with how easy it was to extend my blog generator to generate XML alongside HTML I figured it was better to have a feed than not.…</description>
	<category>software</category><category>website</category>
	<link>https://benleskey.com/blog/made_rss_feed</link>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://benleskey.com/blog/made_rss_feed</guid>
	<pubDate>Sun, 22 Jan 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Mapping tool 0.5 release</title>
	<description>Hello all! Here’s version 0.5 of the mapping tool! You can download it here: https://github.com/mapper1024/mapper1024/blob/master/DOWNLOAD.md#download-options You can use the online demo here: https://mapper1024.github.io/demo Once you’ve tested the new version, please fill out the feedback survey. You can click everything now! One of the primary bits of feedback I received was for a better user interface, and version 0.5 now has a full palette sidebar so that every single control is clickable instead of needing to use the keyboard for everything! The big blob of help text is also much reduced; there are labels, icons, and/or buttons for everything and you…</description>
	<category>mappingtool</category><category>release</category><category>software</category>
	<link>https://benleskey.com/blog/mapper0_5</link>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://benleskey.com/blog/mapper0_5</guid>
	<pubDate>Sat, 21 Jan 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>benleskey.com build script</title>
	<description>This website is static HTML, CSS, and Javascript. There is a build script that compiles together templates and HTML into the final website that you see, this bit of dynamicism enables me to reuse common HTML and keeps track of tedious bits like blog tag link lists. The script—as of writing—that compiles the website is fully commented and included below, along with the data file listing all the blog posts. build.sh posts.sh build.sh posts.sh…</description>
	<category>software</category><category>website</category>
	<link>https://benleskey.com/blog/website_build_script</link>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://benleskey.com/blog/website_build_script</guid>
	<pubDate>Thu, 12 Jan 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Mapping tool 0.4 release</title>
	<description>Hi! Version 0.4 of the mapping tool is out! You can download it here: https://github.com/mapper1024/mapper1024/blob/master/DOWNLOAD.md#download-options You can use the online demo here: https://mapper1024.github.io/demo Once you’ve tested the new version, please fill out the feedback survey. New Renderer and Graphics Version 0.4 of the mapping tool has an updated graphics engine for drawing the maps. Terrain and objects are now represented by small graphical tiles and images for more engaging and easy-to-read maps. The new graphics engine comes with a fully revamped set of graphics for each terrain and object type, along with entirely new terrain and objects. We now have…</description>
	<category>mappingtool</category><category>release</category><category>software</category>
	<link>https://benleskey.com/blog/mapper0_4</link>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://benleskey.com/blog/mapper0_4</guid>
	<pubDate>Wed, 04 Jan 2023 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Mapping tool 0.3 release</title>
	<description>Hello all! The next major version of my map making tool is released! You can download it here: https://github.com/mapper1024/mapper1024/blob/master/DOWNLOAD.md#download-options You can use the online demo here: https://mapper1024.github.io/demo Once you’ve tested the new version, please fill out the feedback survey. What’s New? Version 0.3 of the map making tool includes the following updates: Brush palette — you can select terrain, brush, brush size, and more with only your mouse or touchpad. Good news for laptop users! Smoother graphics — still in prototype stage, but better transitions. Political border support — imaginary boundaries now have a real presence on the map. Prototype…</description>
	<category>mappingtool</category><category>release</category><category>software</category>
	<link>https://benleskey.com/blog/mapper0_3</link>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://benleskey.com/blog/mapper0_3</guid>
	<pubDate>Wed, 26 Oct 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
<item>
	<title>Mapping tool 0.1 release</title>
	<description>Hello! I’m happy to give you and the other testers the first working, testable version of my map making tool designed for authors and storytellers. The map making tool is currently usable to make rudimentary maps, with more improvements on the way–and your feedback is important! You can download it here: https://github.com/mapper1024/mapper1024/blob/master/DOWNLOAD.md#download-options You can use the online demo here: https://mapper1024.github.io/demo If you have any feedback, questions, or need help running the mapping tool, please let me know! Brief Summary The map making tool for authors and storytellers is in the functional prototype stage and ready for you to test. I…</description>
	<category>mappingtool</category><category>release</category><category>software</category>
	<link>https://benleskey.com/blog/mapper0_1</link>
	<guid isPermaLink="true">https://benleskey.com/blog/mapper0_1</guid>
	<pubDate>Mon, 01 Aug 2022 12:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
</item>
_
	</channel>
</rss>
